in this problem
we need to modify the code given so
that the loop stops iterating when the
user inputs
yes so let's run our code as it is
[Music]
and currently no matter what we input
the loop continues
looking back at this code you can see
there is no reserved word break in
our loop so we currently have an
infinite loop every time we run this
code
in order to avoid an infinite loop we
use
the reserved word break if we place
break on
line four of our code
and run it again we'll see that
no matter what our input is
[Music]
our code breaks out of the loop and
that's because we didn't provide our
break statement with any type of
condition
we've just told it that when it reaches
line four
to break out of the loop no matter what
in this problem what we wanted to do is
only break when the user inputs yes
now we're holding the user input in a
local variable called
answer and we can leverage that to
determine
whether the user input was yes
[Music]
so we can compare the value of the
answer to the string yes
[Music]
and now when i input yes you can see
that the loop exits
so that's the desired behavior
now it may be helpful to the user if we
output an
error message if their input is anything
other than yes
[Music]
and now you can see we're explaining to
the user what they need to do in order
to exit
[Music]
you can take this a little further by
doing a little bit of input validation
for example if we run our code and we
input yes with a capital y
our code will not interpret that as yes
because we have our code written to
only break if answer is equal to
the string yes with a lowercase y
there's a few ways we could handle this
we can break if answer is equal to a
lowercase yes
or yes with an uppercase y
you can see our program exits
we can also use the string down case
method on our input when we store it
into the local variable answer
and now even if we type yes in all
capital letters
our program will still recognize that as
yes
so there's a lot you can do with input
validation whether that be
with built-in ruby methods or by writing
out your own logic
and you can explore that more as you
continue to learn more about
ruby